Japanese qualified
to learn this meditation that all seven-
year-olds already do,
which means you have to
invest a lot and concentrate a lot
before you're three, and we're going to do some
for me
[Music]
when you meditate in a group,
then there's a greater
pressure on us
and to be
[Music]
learning a new meditation this week. I don't know,
I'm getting
confused as I get older because
for ten breaths, it hasn't worked for me
anymore. Tried
100 breaths,
the exhalation counts as the first half,
and this inhalation
[Music]
an exchange with someone that was yesterday
or in the last few days,
and starts back,
maybe half an hour that you
spent with someone specific. What did you want to
achieve? What did you want to
take out of this conversation for yourself?
I spent a lot of time with Veronika during that time
because her mother had a
stroke,
and
I had it in the back of my mind
that I wanted to continue working on accessing sex
while I
was with her, and now I think back on it,
what did you want to do? What were
your ulterior motives
during this exchange with a
specific person?
This other person
[Music]
wanted to during this time, assuming
they behaved this way, what was it?
It was that they really wanted it, it was what
they had in mind.
What would you have liked to do during that time, during that time
when he was together?
I think my wife was completely
focused, completely concentrated on
helping my mother, and
[music]
it was what
you wanted to do,
and only do what the other
person had in mind.
But
where were there also important things you
wanted to do?
They always had how they wanted to do things,
and hunger
means maybe a third
alternative, and Bodys has something to think about. Is there
a third solution?
I know what my wife wants to do today, I know
what I want to do today, a
creative way
that we can both do what we
want
and also be together,
still have an interaction
with each other and spend the day
together.
Really, each of us individually gets
what we want
and at the same time creates a third possibility.
Our relationship, our
interaction
[music], where
we are better off
when you do this together. Compared to that,
we would be doing our things alone,
translating, working, and
helping my mother and the other
people my wife helps.
We both had these things to do.
We both have the right
to do what we want, and is there
a really creative way
that we could help each other do
what  Others want it, and that
's even better than if we each do it at the
expense of the other.
That's the way of a god. They do
n't sacrifice what they
want to do.
They don't selfishly do
just what they want,
but they find a creative way so that
everyone gets what they
want at the same time.
So start your exchange with
someone and
consider whether there could have been a third
way
you could have
implemented what each of
you wanted. During that day,
my wife and I set aside some time in the morning,
and we really
enjoyed walking by the sea in California.
We then made an agreement:
maybe she would gather her thoughts for
the day,
or she would figure out how she
could help people that day. During that
time,
I could do some
translation work,
and then we met.
She had already prepared a few things
and what she wanted to do that
day, and I also had my
notes about what I planned for that day.
Yesterday, we compared and
considered how we could both do things that day.
Think about whether you
could do something similar with this other person.
It's something that isn't super creative,
so that no one has to sacrifice anything.  If
both of their goals for the day are
achieved,
then slowly open your eyes.
I think if you're like me,
I remember when I first
came to do this, I had 80
students in New York,
and we came here
to learn.
They had prepared for this for seven years in New York,
and then we came
here to your mountain
to learn the Diamond Way.
Now there are 200,000 students in the
world. There are
about 50
organizations now,
and 200,000 students.
It has grown from 80 to
200,000,
and I
have to focus on
my time management,
and I ca
n't do everything I want with my
wife. I try,
but there are also 200,000 people there.
I have many friends in this room
from those 80 people,
and I
will spend time with them. I
always have some time, but you ca
n't combine 200,000 people the way
you combined 80 people.
We calculated how we could give one
lesson to a thousand
people here.  And it would take over
60 years.
It's not about that; it's about
clever time management.
Since
time is also empty, it can be
stretched or shortened.
And the light that
comes from Mercury to Earth,
the sun,
and the light...
it looks like Mercury slows down a bit
as it passes the
sun. But time is just
a circle;
it's a curve. It takes longer for the
light to reach us after passing the sun.
If you look with a
telescope, you
know you're in the past. It's
time travel, especially with
modern telescopes.
You can be in the past; you
can be directly in the past.
And that's why
the method of combining all
people equally has something to
do with the emptiness of time and space.
And
we can help more people in different ways.
It's
impossible to do
what needs to be done in a normal time frame.
It's impossible to combine
300,000 people with each other
this week and be with my wife
if you don't work with emptiness. So
you need a tool. So, in my
opinion, the
reason why this discussion was
about the fake body cheater is to
question
what the ultimate politician is, because
if you can...  Not helping people differently,
and
countless beings with so many wishes,
dealing with time
better at it,
first
the desire, everyone must be there to help,
100 out of 100,000 people, this desire
must be there,
and that is when you are hungry enough
to serve hundreds of thousands of people,
you will find a way then, when the
human mind is the capacity of the
human mind, and the
way and the possibility that you
can help others is unlimited, we will get there,
we will talk more about it.